# **SYED FARAZ ALI**

Certified HR Analyst & Administration Professional



#### Education

Bachelor of Commerce University of Karachi

Bachelor of Business Administration (Ongoing) Virtual University of Pakistan

## **Professional Competency**

Certified Human Resource Analyst Institute of HR Development-HR Plus

## **Training & Courses**

Labor Laws Applicable to Industries & Obligation of Employers

Human Services Management (Pvt.) Limited

# Contract Labor Management and Relevant Labor Laws

Human Services Management (Pvt.) Limited

# How to Draft Charge Sheet & Conduct Domestic Enquiry

Human Services Management (Pvt.) Limited

## **Digital Marketing**

Digi skills-Ministry of IT & Telecom Pakistan

#### Freelancing

Digi skills-Ministry of IT & Telecom Pakistan

## **Total Quality Management**

Tapal Tea (Pvt.) Limited

## **MS Project 2007 Tools**

Tapal Tea (Pvt.) Limited

#### Microsoft Excel 2003

Tapal Tea (Pvt.) Limited

## **English Language Program**

Tapal Tea (Pvt.) Limited

#### Microsoft Access, In-house Training

Muller & Phipps Pakistan (Pvt.) Limited

## **Computer Skills**

Microsoft Office
Microsoft Excel
Microsoft Access
Microsoft Visio
Microsoft Power Point
Microsoft Outlook,
Oracle HR Module

Oracle Procurement Module Inpage Urdu Software

Cell: 0300-2123762

E-Mail: faraz97@hotmail.com; faraz1976@gmail.com

Web: <a href="http://pk.linkedin.com/in/farazasyed">http://pk.linkedin.com/in/farazasyed</a>

Skype faraz.97
FB <u>faraz.a.syed</u>
Twitter @faraz1976

## **Professional Summary**

Introducing myself as result oriented, initiative, flexible with any working environment, confident, can handle any task in any situation with positive and professional approach.

Almost 21 years diversified experience in General Administration, Safety & Security Infrastructure, Fleet Administration, Human Resources Operations, Recruitment & Contract, Training & Development, Employees Relations, Industrial Relations, Procurement, etc. Very active in Social Media activities e.g. LinkedIn, FB, Twitter, etc.

Worked in different industries or Sectors, e.g. Manufacturing, FMCG, Distribution, Shipping & Logistics, Supply Chain, Automotive, etc. and got a lot of experience of multiple environments and corporate culture. It was a pleasure to work with the large scale organizations, business tycoons, Proprietor Ships and with ex-service men, which always educate me to handle with difficult situations and learnt how to deal with stressful environments and to complete the tasks within stipulated timelines.

## **Work Experience**

Manager HR & Administration
Jan. 2015 to May 2019

➤ Manager Administration & Procurement Feb. 2014 to Jan. 2015

➤ Manager HR & Administration Apr. 2013 to Jan. 2014

Manager HR & Administration Nov. 2010 to Apr. 2013

Projects Executive (Procurement & Compliance) June 2006 to Oct. 2010

Sr. Officer – Recruitment & Org. Dev. Dec. 1996 to June 2005 Aleph International, (Textile & Safety Products)

Toyota Southern Motors (Automotive)

Al-Hamd Int'l Container Terminal (Off Dock Terminal)

AB Engineering (Pvt.) Limited (Automotive)

Tapal Tea (Pvt.) Limited, (FMCG)

Muller & Phipps Pak. (Pvt.) Limited, (Logistics/Supply Chain)

#### **Area of Expertise**

## Human Resource /IR /ER

Recruitment
Performance Management
Training & Development
Industrial Relations
Employees Relations
Payroll Management

Policies/SOP's Administration Dealing with CBA/NIRC

#### Administration / Procurement

General Administration Fleet Administration House Keeping

Safety & Security Management

Facility Management Construction/Renovation

Procurement/Vendor Management

Warehouse Administration

#### Job Responsibilities

#### Human Resource/Industrial or Employee Relations:

- Recruitment, Planning & Development, Annual Appraisal /Increment, Training and Development of Staff.
- Design and execution of HR, Administration, Supply Chain, Technical, Production and Procurement Standard Operating Procedures and Manuals.
- Performed HR Generalist Role.
- Preparation of job descriptions and key performance indicators for each position.
- Revamping of Organizational Structure.
- Performance Management. Preparation of evaluation statements, reports, charts & comparative statements for departmental needs as well as required by other departments or top Management.

## SYED FARAZ ALI

## Certified HR Analyst & Administration Professional

## **Personal Information:**

Address: House No. R-98, Sector R-1,

Near Masjid Abdul Aziz Noor,

Gulshan-e-Maymar, Karachi

Father's Name: Syed Liaquat Ali
CNIC No.: 42101-5813574-1
Date of Birth: April 2, 1976
Contact: 021-36832199

Passport No.: XM1795742 (13/09/2020)

NTN No.: 1269413-4

EOBI No.: 080-0E-130744 (06/06/2006)

040-0C-112736 (15/12/1996)

DL No.: CLA 1351772

(42101-5813574-1#511)

## References:

#### Mr. Ageel Ahmed Khan

Technical Manager Allied Engineering Contact No. 0300-8989114

#### Mr. Fida Ali Mirza

CEO / Executive Director AB Eng. / AICT Contact No. 0333-2141412

- Arrange to prepare leave record of all employees in all establishments of Organization. Maintain Employee's personal files & records; arrange to prepare Company Identity Cards of Employees
- Departmental business goals, Budgeting of Personnel & Admin. Department /Human Resource Division.
- EOBI, ESSI, CBA, NIRC, Labour Department, Legal advisors & consultants.
- Conflict Resolution, Employees Grievances. Perform and participate as Enquiry Officer and complainant as well in various enquiries on violation of rules & regulations, misconduct of employees.
- Payroll Management and disbursement. Attendance System.
- Group Hospitalization Insurance, Group life and Accidental Insurance Schemes.

#### Administration/Procurement:

- General Administration, Facility Management, Security Administration
- Designing and execution of Administration Manuals and SOP's.
- Compliance of Health Safety & Environmental ISO Standards.
- Development of Safety and environment Infrastructure. Identification of unsafe acts, conditions & hazards.
- · Event Planning & Management.
- Janitorial and general Administration Work.
- Fleet Management, Vehicle purchasing, repairing & Maintenance. Travel Log Management, Tracking Systems, Insurance, Registration, Taxes, etc.
- Cafeteria services and entertainment facilities for staff. Event Management.
- Deal with local Government and Associations, e.g. CDGK, KDA, SITE, KATI, etc.
- Construction, Maintenance, renovation of the premises
- Prepare Agreements & correspondence with contractors and consultants.
- Maintain proper records of underway / completed projects. Lease and Contracts Management.
- Store/Warehouse Management, Inventory Management.
- Procurement Planning & Budgeting.
- Vendor evaluation, Pre-Qualification, Suppliers Assessment, Vendor Management, General Order Suppliers.
- Procurement of material, equipment's, machinery and office supplies, etc.
- Arrangement of material, equipment's, office supplies, etc. according to QCD.
- Hands on experience of Oracle related activities e.g. Requisitions, work/purchase orders capital
  expenditures, etc.
- Well versed with Oracle Supply Chain Module.
- Deal with General Order Suppliers or different super Stores (Metro Cash & Carry, Imtiaz, etc.)
   regarding supplies and purchases.

#### **Achievements**

#### **Aleph International**

- Completed Pre-Qualifications of Foreign Clients.
- Successfully organize and developed all Manuals and SOPs' for the Department of HR, Administration, Procurement, and Production according to International Standards.

#### AB Engineering (Pvt.) Ltd.

- Successfully build up Department of HR & Administration. Revamp Raw material and Finished goods Warehouses. Introduce Kaizen and Employee recognition System.
- Developed all Manuals, SOPs' & WIS for HR, Administration, Production and Warehouses.

#### Tapal Tea (Pvt.) Limited

- Consecutive appraised as exceed performer from 2008-2010.
- Introduce smart & intelligent tracking system and costing of Projects administrative tasks.
- Initiate Rehabilitation of Electrical Infrastructure, conducted survey and analysis of Head Office.
- Successfully look after Agriculture Farmhouse of CEO and get the highest sale in 2010 since last 30 years.

#### Muller & Phipps Pakistan (Pvt.) Limited

- Team member for in house development and launch of Oracle based HRM-IS.
- Successfully arrange and participate to reorganize Administration and Human Resources Departments.